<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.13">
  <compounddef id="interfaceCqrs_1_1Commands_1_1ICommandHandle" kind="interface" language="C#" prot="public">
    <compoundname>Cqrs::Commands::ICommandHandle</compoundname>
    <basecompoundref refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Messages_1_1IHandler" prot="public" virt="non-virtual">Cqrs.Messages.IHandler</basecompoundref>
    <derivedcompoundref refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Commands_1_1ICommandHandler" prot="public" virt="non-virtual">Cqrs.Commands.ICommandHandler&lt; TAuthenticationToken, in in TCommand &gt;</derivedcompoundref>
    <briefdescription>
<para>An ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; receives an ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; and brokers a result from the appropriate IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;. &quot;A result&quot; is either a successful application of the command, or an exception. This is the common sequence of steps an ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; might follow: </para>    </briefdescription>
    <detaileddescription>
<para>Validate the ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; on its own merits. Ask an IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; to handle the ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;. If validation is successful, 0..n IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; artefacts (1 is common) are queued for publishing. Attempt to persist the new IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; artefacts. If there&apos;s a concurrency conflict during this step, either give up, or retry things. Dispatch the queued IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; artefacts. </para><para>Should a ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; affect one or several IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;s?</para><para>Only one.</para><para>Do I put logic in ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;?</para><para>Yes. Exactly what logic depends on your factoring. The logic for validating the ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; on its own merits always gets executed in the ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;, although we recommend refactoring these into an ICommandValidator&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;. Provided validation is successful we recommend a more functional factoring, where the IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; exists independently of the ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; and the next step would be to load the IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; from the IUnitOfWork&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; and request the IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; handle the ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; itself. The IUnitOfWork&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; should then have uncommitted IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; artefacts as a results of asking the IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; to handle the ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;. Finally the ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; should instruct the IUnitOfWork&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; to IUnitOfWork&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;.Commit all uncommited IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; artefacts.</para><para>However you have it, the logic boils down to validation and some sequence of steps that lead to the ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; becoming an Exception or IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;(s). If you&apos;re tempted to go beyond this, see the rest of the remarks.</para><para>Can I call a read side (such as a read store, data store or IAggregateRepository&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;) from my ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;?</para><para>No.</para><para>Can I do logging, security, or auditing in my ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;?</para><para>Yes. The decorator pattern comes in handy here to separate those concerns neatly.</para><para>How are conflicts between concurrent ICommand&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;s handled in the ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;?</para><para>The place where the new IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; artefacts for the IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; are persisted is the only place in the system where we need to worry about concurrency conflicts. The IEventStore&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; knows the sequence number of the latest IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; applied on that IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;, and the ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; knows the sequence number of the last IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; it read. If these numbers do not agree, it means some other thread or process got there first. The ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; can then load up the events again and make a new attempt.</para><para>Should I do things that have side-effects in the outside world (such as sending email) directly in a ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt;?</para><para>No, since a concurrency conflict will mean the ICommandHandler&lt;TAuthenticationToken,TCommand&gt; logic will be run again. Do such things in an Apply IEvent&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt; method in an IAggregateRoot&lt;TAuthenticationToken&gt;. <hruler/>
 Also see <ulink url="http://cqrs.nu/Faq/command-handlers">http://cqrs.nu/Faq/command-handlers</ulink>. </para>    </detaileddescription>
    <inheritancegraph>
      <node id="1107">
        <label>Cqrs.Commands.ICommandHandle</label>
        <link refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Commands_1_1ICommandHandle"/>
        <childnode refid="1108" relation="public-inheritance">
        </childnode>
      </node>
      <node id="1108">
        <label>IHandler</label>
        <link refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Messages_1_1IHandler"/>
      </node>
      <node id="1109">
        <label>Cqrs.Commands.ICommandHandler&lt; TAuthenticationToken, in in TCommand &gt;</label>
        <link refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Commands_1_1ICommandHandler"/>
        <childnode refid="1107" relation="public-inheritance">
        </childnode>
      </node>
    </inheritancegraph>
    <collaborationgraph>
      <node id="1110">
        <label>Cqrs.Commands.ICommandHandle</label>
        <link refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Commands_1_1ICommandHandle"/>
        <childnode refid="1111" relation="public-inheritance">
        </childnode>
      </node>
      <node id="1111">
        <label>IHandler</label>
        <link refid="interfaceCqrs_1_1Messages_1_1IHandler"/>
      </node>
    </collaborationgraph>
    <location file="/mnt/c/code/git/CQRS.XsamX/Framework/Cqrs/Commands/ICommandHandler.cs" line="122" column="1" bodyfile="/mnt/c/code/git/CQRS.XsamX/Framework/Cqrs/Commands/ICommandHandler.cs" bodystart="121" bodyend="123"/>
    <listofallmembers>
    </listofallmembers>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
